For those of you that don't know me, I
guess you can see it on the screen. My
name is Dimitri. Um
I'm super excited to geek out with you
for an hour or so. Actually, thank you
for showing up and being my audience.
And and that gets me a break from
actually, you know, going and doing work
uh to run this company that I'm running.
Oh.
Oh, cool. Okay, good. And um uh second
man, seems like I disappeared. Uh and
then um
and I get to geek out with you on on
these crazy new things that that we're
all experiencing together. So, thanks
for being here. Uh I'm going to share my
screen. And again, I'm going to start
with kind of framing all of this for us.
I'm going to try to do this in like 15
to 20 minutes kind of at at
at most. And then we'll get into like
all the nitty-gritty and I'll show you
my setup and I'll show you, you know, a
bunch of these things that you may not
have thought of that are actually really
important when if you choose to play
around with configuring the these
personal agents, all right? Uh
chat is open for questions. Uh at the
end of this, I am going to allow uh
probably 10 minutes for question and
answer. And then afterwards, if we don't
get to your questions, uh we're going to
route those questions to like uh oh, I
know where we're going to route them.
We're going to route them
here to the school community. Okay, so
this is a free uh community thing that I
and Marilynn Nica uh who I co-teach
with, uh runs. It's completely free to
join. We just post all our stuff there.
And so, if you've got questions
afterwards, cuz we always sort of end up
leaving before we're answering all the
questions, feel free, join, and post
questions there and I promise I'll
answer every single question that's
that's posted, in including on my new
haircut here.
So, my my wife and I are joking how she
cut my hair this time. Okay, let's get
into this.
Um
Uh okay, I can see you guys can see my
screen. Uh okay, so again, I'm these
days I describe myself as an old nerd.
In my day job, I run a venture-backed
company
uh called Mind Studio. It's now changing
its name to Remy. Prior to this, I spent
4 years at Google on the product side. I
was CTO at MySpace Music, if any of you
remember that time. Um I also built two
other venture-backed companies. One was
actually quite a large competitor to
YouTube called Veo. Another one was a
cybersecurity company Aconyx. I've now
raised over $140 million in venture
capital, blah blah blah. The only reason
I'm telling you all this stuff so you
kind of know I'm I'm just a geek. I love
this stuff. I started writing code in
1984. I'm more excited about software
than I've ever been. And I've been you
can find me online of being excited
about all kinds of things. This is
crazy. Uh here in this company we've
raised 36 million. Again, this session
is not about the company, so I'm not
going to spend any time on it, but it's
in the business of of allowing people to
build AI agents. So kind of By the way,
the entire company is this.
I'm CEO. Sean is CTO. We have one
product manager, one engineer, Marco.
And the this is the company. Okay, why?
Because well, we're in a new world,
right? We're we're living in this agenda
world where you can automate things. And
you shouldn't. If you're not automating
things, then you've come to the right
place. You should be doing it.
Uh these There's a lot of hype out there
if you pay any attention to, you know,
the the inner webs about all kinds of
things. This thing called open claw gone
crazy, you know, China um um again, big
craze in China for this. Uh
Facebook bought this thing called
Molbook,
uh which is a social network for these
open claw agents. So this is what we're
going to be talking about today about
We're going to be specifically focused
on Hermes, which is the agent I'm
currently running. But, what I'm going
to show you actually transfers to all
these other agents. They all work the
same way. They've got small differences
about them, and I'll point some out.
But, like all the stuff you're going to
learn here today, you can take and just
give it to any other agent, and it will
implement the same thing and do things
generally in the same way. Okay, so like
what are these things?
Uh kind of the most popular one that you
may have seen out in the news is the
thing called Open Claw, okay? And Open
Claw, again, was built by this guy Peter
Steinberger, went viral, and then uh
OpenAI bought it. And and uh and here it
is now. And then there's a bunch of
other ones of these things that are
either known as claws,
c l a w s claws, or I like to call them
personal agents. I'm about to explain to
you what a personal agent even is, but
first I'll show you some of these names
you might see out and about that all
cluster together as being personal
agents. So, Open Claw, Hermes, Think
Out, Nano Claw, which is just a very
slimmed-down version of these things.
Um it's got some better security,
something called Zero Claw, which is
super super slimmed-down. It can run on
like super low-power devices.
Uh Nvidia has one of their own that's
specifically made for enterprises to be
a little bit more secure, more
containerized. Oh, and by the way, you
don't need to use any of these. Even if
you've never written a line of code, you
can go to like uh Claude Code or to uh
Codex or to Anti-gravity and simply copy
and paste this. Like here's the link to
this thing where Open Claw lives, how
can we build a better one, and these
things will build you one of these
personal agents. There's countless other
personal agents that people have built.
Uh I have used all of these except for
uh Zero Claw.
Um and uh currently I'm running Hermes,
and there's a bunch of things I'm doing
with this. We're going to dive into
these in the again, the second section
after I get through all the the stuff at
the top. By the way, I'm going to give
all of you guys in that school community
access to this entire Excalidraw, so you
will have all of this as soon as I'm get
done with the class. Last time I shared
it early and everybody came in and I
started seeing everybody's mouse
mice moving around and and it got kind
of rowdy, so I'm I'm going to wait till
I'm done to share this with you. So for
now, just look at it. But again, you'll
have access to all the stuff, so don't
worry. I'm like I'm not skipping
anything. Okay.
Um so like so what? Like why are we even
talking about these
personal [clears throat] agents? Uh
well, what what's the big deal? I mean,
there's a lot of stuff going on in AI.
Why aren't we talking about like image
and video models and you know, countless
other things.
Um okay, so this is really important. So
um
a personal agent uh also known as a
another word for something like this is
called a harness. Now, a harness uh can
be used for more than personal agents,
but a personal agent all personal agents
are harnesses, not all harnesses are
personal agents. But a personal a
personal agent something called a
harness is just a piece of software that
somebody wrote that you can download
from the internet
uh and then when you configure it, when
you install it after down downloading
it, when you go through the onboarding,
it asks you to authenticate it with a
model provider to give it access to a
model.
And and you can use any model. All these
things are basically model agnostic, so
you can use OpenAI, Anthropic, Google,
Meta, Mistral, whatever. And once you
give it access,
you download this harness, this personal
agent, and in onboarding, you connect it
to a model, well, what you've created
now is a personal agent.
And this harness, what does it do? Well,
it allows a model to operate your
computer, to control your computer.
I suspect you all know or or at least
may have seen in the news, that these
models, especially this new generate the
latest generation of models, are
incredible at writing code, right? And
and that there's lots of developers that
are being displaced by this, and lots of
companies are really leaning into this
to allow these things. And and this is
true. These models are exceptional at
writing code. They're like the best
developers in the world, basically.
Certainly unlike any developer you'd be
able to recruit to your company to do
your job. So, they're basically the best
developers in the world, and they're
available to you to simply connect your
computer and say, "You, best developer
in the world, help me operate my
computer."
Right. Well, what's the point of that?
Why would you want to let a model
operate your computer? Well, it can do
the same thing on your computer you can
do. It can use your browser, it can send
and receive emails, and run your
calendar, and connect to all your
software, and follow your, you know,
standard operating procedures, and make
sure that it's aligning to your OKRs,
and like do all of that stuff. It can
use your computer. It's like um
if you go out and buy a a regular car,
well, you have to, you know, drive it.
But, if you go out and buy a Tesla,
well, you can put it in self-driving
mode, and it can drive it. This sort of
the same thing. This is like
self-driving for your computer, any
computer, Mac, PC, Linux.
You just download one of these agents,
you got a bunch to choose from, you
connect them to a model, that's easy,
just log into the model,
and now they can drive your computer.
And so, they can read and write files,
obviously, and they can run these things
called terminal commands, or bash, or
shell commands. Meaning, if you don't
know what these are, some of you might
be old enough to remember DOS, you know,
back in the day, or like if you've seen
like hacker movies, you'll see hackers
aren't like moving their mouse around
and clicking through windows, they're
like typing stuff in this terminal it's
called.
This thing can do that. It knows all the
terminal commands, and how to think
about really, really being able to get
the most out of a a computer.
And all you need to do is download a
personal agent harness, connect it to a
model,
and tell it what you want it to do. By
the way, that's where the hard part is.
It's figuring out, well,
great, but
self-driving, but I don't know what what
to tell it to do and how to tell it to
do it and all of that. And that's what
we're about to get into, yeah? Uh by the
way, there is a ton of amazing material
on all of this. I'm certainly not the
only person geeking out on these things.
Uh
if you go to YouTube and just look for
harness engineering or personal agents
or automate with AI or whatever, you'll
find, uh you know, thousands and
thousands of videos. Uh Y Combinator's
got a whole series they've been doing. I
highly recommend this. Um they're I
think they're [clears throat] just
killing it with content production. It's
really valuable. They've got really
interesting vantage point. Again, I'll
link these for you you guys later,
you'll be able to watch them. You'll
find lots and lots of other stuff that's
out there. There's also a link here to
this boot camp that I do with Marily
Nika. Feel free and visit it. The next
cohort starts
um July 20th. And by the way, there we
really dive into this. It's a 3-week
thing where we get much more into the
guts, not 1 hour. Okay. So,
these things are awesome. You should
play around with them. And And I'm going
to kind of pause here for a moment to to
accentuate this word play. I think at
this moment, my recommendation to you is
not to take this overly seriously. Like
meaning, should you choose harnesses,
open claw, don't don't worry about that.
Probably none of these are the things
that are the long-term things, okay?
But, learning how to Installing is
trivially easy. That That's not a thing.
But, learning how to configure a
personal agent and then how to leverage
it. This is a new skill set that we all
need to learn together, yeah? And I
encourage you just think of it as play,
experimentation. Use this agent,
configure it in this way. Use a
different agent configure it in
different way, see what you like about
them and like really try to get your
bearings of like what this means. Think
about your own workflow, your company's
workflow and what you could do with
these things because you can do that.
Anything that any people in your company
do in front of the computer
you can get these personal agents to do
those things.
That's crazy.
But that this is where we are. This is
reality now. Okay. Okay, but let's talk
uh some more uh again quickly before we
get into my configuration. And again, I
also want to point out to you as I show
you my configuration, my configuration
should not be your configuration. Like
you're welcome to have it. I'll give it
to you. You'll see I'll give you
documents. You can have my
configuration. But the whole point of
this is that this thing needs to help
you do what you need to do. And you're
not me. I've got other things I need to
do. And so I want to throughout this
class kind of inspire you not to say,
"Oh, I got to like think about what
Dmitri did." No, no, no, don't do that.
I'm just one experiment that I'm showing
you and diving deep because I've been
geeking out on this stuff. Uh and and
you'll benefit from it, I'm sure. But
yeah, don't try to just copy that. Okay.
Um 3 years ago, I I I have a Substack
and uh 3 years ago
in May of May 3rd, 2023, I wrote an
article called the human AI interface.
There I argued
>> [clears throat]
>> that even 3 years ago, this is when
ChatGPT first came out, we were already
in a place for decades
where we humans were the bottleneck to
being able to leverage all of the
applications that are available to us.
Like how many apps in the App Store,
let's say productivity apps that we
could download and install and implement
into our workflow and be able to benefit
from them. Countless. We could never
download and install all of them and
benefit from them, right? Or even pick
which ones to download. And apps for
editing video and and and and Figma and
like countless apps that we needed to
learn to use, become proficient at
using, be able to make time to use.
But there was countless more that we
could we could have done if we had the
resources to do it. Meaning, there's
only 24 hours in a day. Okay, so we're
the bottle now before AI.
Now with AI, again, 3 years ago I
predicted that this was just going to
get crazy. Now, did I predict this much
craziness?
I didn't. Meaning not so quickly at
least. Uh and so I I I said that what
you're going to need in order to be able
to leverage all this innovation is to to
create some kind of called it UAI, some
personal digital agent that itself is AI
that can leverage all the new innovation
that's happening in the space,
accelerating. And your job and it's
becomes your proxy. And your job is to
maintain a relationship with it kind of
like people who are very powerful and
very rich have, you know, chiefs of
staff, personal assistants, family
offices.
And uh you know, they don't need to do
the same thing we need to do up at a
computer. Again, I recently took my
family to Disneyland. I had to plan it
with my wife. That was like a bunch of
work. You know, people richer than me
don't have to plan it. They tell their
assistant, I'd like to take the family
to Disneyland and they plan all of it.
They never have to type anything, look
up any websites, and do any of this
stuff. Okay.
Excuse [clears throat] me. Um
Uh and so again, it's an amazing place
that we find ourselves in. I think we're
all lucky here together that we're
paying attention to this. You know, our
colleagues and other people on outside
that aren't in this room now are
generally potentially oblivious to this.
They know something is happening, but
they don't yet know that this thing
is is a ginormous
uh uh uh um
event horizon
that uh
once you once uh
you understand that you understand why
Jensen Huang, the CEO of Nvidia,
recently said that open claw is the new
computer. It's a bold statement. He also
said it was it's the most important
software that's ever been created. Well,
I was like I mean, some paraphrase, but
basically implied that, which which, you
know, I think he's overstating it, but
I know what he means, meaning when you
give a computer
in
uh self-driving
and that and the driver is a modern
frontier model. Well, that's a whole
other thing of computing, okay? But, of
course, today we still struggle as
humans to try to understand what this
is. That's why I said this is like
artificial intelligence. That's us, but
we've always been, you know, using
horses. And so, our mental model is the
thing that stands in our way. I think
with all of this, this is why I also
encourage you guys to continue to
experiment on the the the key is to get
over this, to figure this out. I think
that's kind of the most important thing.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Uh here you will see step-by-step
instructions to install the Hermes
agent. Again, when I give you this
thing, you guys can follow these
instructions. There's nothing I need to
do here to help you install it. You can
install Hermes, you can install open
claw. Again, all these things I'm going
to show you are going to work the same
across all of these things. There'll be
small nuances, but they're irrelevant.
Okay? Um
>> [clears throat]
>> Uh
I've tried a bunch of them. Again, so if
you want my opinion at this point to
friends and family and and everybody
else, extended friends and family,
I think Hermes is the is the winner
right now and and the easiest one to get
going and really feel the power of
things. And so, I guess I I could say I
have recommend. I have no relationship
with them. I'm not sponsored or anything
like that. But, this is cool. The other
thing that I recommend is this Hermes
desktop application.
Uh so, I too am running it
here somewhere.
Uh
there we go. Oops, it's on another
screen here. Um, and um,
And yeah, so this is a an
an electron app that you can download.
It gives you a bunch of your sessions
and agents. You can see all of your
skills and like all of these other
things that are part of it. You can
easily switch models. You can see how
many tokens you're using. You can see
how much your context length. By the
way, if you don't know any of these
terms, don't worry about it. You don't
need to know any of these terms. But
this is a free application. You can just
install and it makes it easier to manage
Hermes and to use Hermes. And so I I
typically stay away from desktop apps,
but this one has been really valuable.
So I do encourage you guys to to try it.
Okay. Mostly again, you communicate with
this thing via chat. And so Telegram is
is common. I do communicate with it via
uh, Telegram.
Uh, but if I'm at my computer, I
communicate with it via this desktop
app. And you'll see I have to do some
additional things to set this up. And
that's what we're about to dive into.
Like kind of the nooks and crannies of
what it takes to make this stuff work.
>> [clears throat]
>> Um,
Okay, I see people already complaining
about this being session two and not
session one. Again, I apologize. There
are folks here who've seen some of this
material
Excuse [clears throat] me, in the last
session, but most folks I think have
not. And so I'm trying to very quickly
get through this. By the way, all of
this is available in the prior video you
can find on our school. Okay. Uh,
and and and get it there on YouTube,
basically. You can see it. So I'm about
to fast forward. Okay.
Um, okay. Um,
So, uh,
Yeah, actually this is a perfect timing.
We're we're basically done with this
thing. And so now I want to quickly take
you into, again, the
showing you things in here actually
isn't very valuable to help you
understand what this thing is. So I'm
actually going to stay outside of Hermes
itself to show you what these things are
cuz here they're just sort of, you know,
they're back-end things and so they're
hidden. But, this is my primary
interface on desktop to Hermes.
On mobile, it's Telegram. But, I want to
show you what's behind the scenes. So,
again, there's like these documents. All
three of these documents are going to be
available All four of these documents
are going to be available for you
instantly after this session ends. So,
don't worry about taking notes or any of
that. Okay.
Um
>> [clears throat]
>> So, one document I'm going to give you
is this Hermes agent setup. Again, you
can go through it and set this up. Um
there's nothing here very
uh you know, specific or interesting
that you need to know.
Uh you need to pick a model that you're
going to use.
I'll give you some
advice on choosing API versus
subscription connection. I'm running the
Anthropic subscription connection
with my Hermes agent. Okay. Yeah, I'm I
want to skip through this install stuff
because again, people have seen it and
there's more interesting stuff. You guys
can read this document, follow along.
It's easy to do.
Um with uh open claw,
you know, 60 to 70% of time it worked
and then like 30 to 40% I'd spend a
bunch of time troubleshooting it. So
far, every time I've installed Hermes,
it's worked. So, I expect you guys will
have a similar experience. If it doesn't
for some reason, open up a new tab in
your browser, connect to your model of
choice, and
copy and paste some of the errors you
get and it'll tell you what command to
type and whatever and then you'll be
done. Okay.
Okay. The other thing you're going to
need to do is configure this what's
known as a search API. These agents are
again, harnesses that are connected to
models. The models have training and
lots of knowledge, but the models
constantly have a need for searching and
getting more information and
fact-checking and doing lots of things.
And so, you're going to need a search
API. There's many available.
Here I'm I'm
uh
I've used I think
maybe all or most certainly most of the
ones that Hermes recommends by default.
I think this one is better for a bunch
of reasons. I give them to you here.
Again, I'm not going to go through it
here. You guys can read it. Uh use any
API you want, but this one is the one I
use.
Uh also I as I say here if you're
dealing with like financial data and and
like real-time stuff is important, I
find this is the only one that makes
sense for that. So, there you go. Okay,
another thing that's very important to
my setup uh is this thing called Gbrain,
okay? So, Gbrain is
uh again a free software that's
available on GitHub built by Garry Tan,
who's the CEO of Y Combinator,
um
uh you know, it's like a giant incubator
for for startups. And he's built this
long-term memory system that allows in
this case I'll keep talking about me,
but obviously also you
uh to easily install this thing, you
need to get a couple of API keys for it
from from some third-party providers.
And then this thing is ingests
all of my email and and Slack and um
and contacts and like all the surfaces,
Zoom, where there's data about people
and companies and entities and puts it
all into one basically database
uh and it creates a graph, a knowledge
graph that connects all of them that's
multi-dimensional. Actually, let me see
if I can quickly uh show you this. So,
another piece of software I'm running is
something called Parsec. Uh it's in one
of these documents here that I'll show
you. It allows me to connect now for
um you know, desktop sharing with
Watson. Watson is my open claw sorry,
it's my Hermes agent. It runs on another
machine that's here on my desk. And so,
I'm working on one machine. Now I'm
connecting to another machine and this
is a piece of software called Obsidian.
Again, all of this is linked in these
documents. And Obsidian is
in this case basically the back end of
being able to store these markdown files
for all the memory of over 10,000 people
that are now in my database. And all of
these things here are various nodes of
people and entities that, you know, I
can get into and click on them and see
how they're connected and open up, you
know, various information about them
that that's in this database. Okay. And
and so G brain powers all of this. It
powers creating that graph. It power it
it does something called vectorization
where it turns all of these things into
vector embeddings. And therefore I can
do semantic search on it. I can do a a
query like show me all the people
basically my 10,000 people
that have been posting about some topic
on Twitter.
And this thing can pull those people up
for me. Or
show me all the people and rank them
that can get me in touch with some
person that I'm not connected to. Well,
it knows who I'm connected to on
LinkedIn and Twitter and email and
contacts. And because everything is
linked and I can ask these kinds of
questions. This thing is able to give me
these kinds of lists of people. It's
incredible. It's it's insane.
I highly recommend this. It's completely
free. Again, Gary Tan's kind of on fire
and building really cool things. I also
in my boot camp we teach this and also
something called G stack which is
another thing that Gary built which
helps you code dramatically better with
Claude code. And that's really powerful.
Okay. So anyway, so G brain is a big
part
of [clears throat] the stack. Again, to
install it you literally just copy this
into your agent into your Hermes and
paste it in and hit enter. And then
you're ready to go. Okay.
And And um, you know, because of that
uh uh
you know, the countless use cases for
something like that. Again, yours might
be different than mine. For me, one of
the use cases has been again this like
smart contacts. It ingest my email,
calendar, Zoom, Twitter, LinkedIn,
contacts. It goes off and enriches all
of them. Enriches means goes and does
deep research to get more information
about them than they found in my email
or they found on Twitter and they found
on LinkedIn. Okay? Again, we'll talk
about some of these custom that I've got
here
in this document here in a moment. And
and it allows me to have
a contacts database, a CRM of my
relationships that I've always wanted
and never had. Uh and now I have it and
and I'm still learning to figure out
what to do with it. So,
like I said, the the you know, that
picture of the horse and the carriage
but in the car but
but
profoundly valuable stuff. Highly
recommend playing around. Okay. Again,
Obsidian is you know, G brain suggests
Obsidian. Uh you can download it for
free. You don't need to learn to use it
other than to like to look at your graph
and be able to look at this. It's
basically the front end to G brain. The
easiest way to see G brain is either
talk to your agent and your agent can
tell you who in your database matches
this whatever or let me list etc. Or G
brain allow or Obsidian allows you to
like visualize it. And if you like that
kind of thing, there's some valuable
things that can that can come out of
that. But as it says, like all of this
sort of like barely scratches the
surface of all of this. Another thing
that's important So, sorry, we're still
going through setup here. Like I think
this is really important even those of
you that have heard it before last time,
uh you should do these things if I think
you want to get the most out of this
like kind of state of the art thing of
this. Another thing very important is to
set up activity dependent model
selection as I call it. Meaning when you
choose a model uh when you set up
Hermes, it has you choose
your default model. What model do you
want to use? And that's the default
model. Uh they actually suggest that you
initially choose the most powerful model
of whatever provider you want as you're
setting up Hermes. So, Opus in this case
in Anthropic. Uh but then once you kind
of have it generally set up in the first
session, you need to tell it something
like this, implement activity dependent
model selection. You just copy and paste
this. Uh again, in this case I'm running
Anthropic, so I say Sonnet is the
default model. Everyday tasks other than
writing meaningful code.
Opus, when you need to write meaningful
chunk of code, use this model. And
Haiku, that's the cheapest, when you
just need to do like simple
summarization, parsing content, all
these things that don't require
actually, you know, reasoning, use the
cheap model. And by doing that, it
dramatically lowers your bill. If you
just leave it on, I'm going to use Opus
all the time, it gets expensive. Or
again, if you're using your
subscription, you might hit rate limits
uh or, you know, run out of uh credits
on your on your plan.
Um okay. And then um the other things
that I think again are are really
important to do is set up uh
uh some of these fundamental processes
uh like this thing I have called daily
inefficiency scan. We're about to really
talk about these in depth that runs uh
every night and basically looks at all
the things that have changed today in
our system or constantly updating.
Again, all of this is like growing and
moving and new capabilities are being
added. Hermes learns the more it does
things. It takes notes and creates
skills and updates skills in order to do
it better. So, the system every day is
just naturally, just by you using it and
it doing things for you, is learning and
getting better.
And so, things are changing.
And there can be all kinds of
inefficiencies that get introduced and
runaway processes and security
vulnerabilities and all of that. And so
you need things that run on an ongoing
basis that do things. I've got
at this moment
cron jobs, 21 of these cron jobs that
are running. Cron is a Unix command for
running scheduled things. And so this
just means these things run on a
schedule and and yeah, on various times.
Uh and and we're about to jump into
that. By the way, one last thing on this
document is if you go here, I give you a
link. This is the company that makes
Hermes agent and they've got this whole
sort of directory of use cases. So if
you're like, I don't know what to do
with this thing, I want some
inspiration, blah blah blah, you can go
here and there's like countless things
here. Okay, let's dive into things that
certainly people have not seen
in the last class cuz I just made them
or last couple of days. Um
okay, um so this is basically what I'm
calling Watson's stack. So Watson is the
name of my Hermes agent. So when I say
Watson, I just mean my implementation of
Hermes. It's also been an implementation
close to two dozen times of, you know,
open claw and you know, all these other
claws basically. Okay, so
some things you guys already heard. So
let me make this a bit bigger here for
you. I use Anthropic. You can use any
model providers you want. You do want to
use nice frontier models that are
capable. You absolutely can run open
source models. You can use Hermes
with models that are running locally on
your computer. So if you have like a
gaming machine that's got a GPU or
you've got like a Mac Studio or some
nice machine that can run a
a good model, you can run models
basically for free other than the cost
of electricity on your computer and
connect Hermes to use that. And that's
if you've got that, use it. That's super
valuable, you know, cost control is
good. I use Anthropic. I'm just using
our team's. So we We a team subscription
plan. That's what I'm using for this. I
also have built here
a what I call mission control that
monitors for me spend. And so, I can
actually see the spend if I wasn't using
uh our plan. Uh and typically this goes
into, you know, anywhere from like
30 bucks a day. This just got reset.
This says 35
200s if you're not Again, if you're not
switching models, if you're always using
Opus, this thing can easily get into the
hundreds a day of doing a lot of things.
This is my mission control. We'll cover
this a little bit later. This is another
view. I actually had
you know, I vibe coded this with my
Hermes agent with Watson and this is my
custom one. Again, you guys can have
this also if you want to implement this
exact same thing or modified in some
way.
>> [clears throat]
>> Um so, all you need to do is is make
sure that you got some access to a
model. The other thing is if you're
using G brain, if you choose to use G
brain
Excuse me, guys.
Um
it would uh
one of the things that it does that's
really, really valuable is not only
again, hold these markdown files on your
computer where it basically creates this
graph of all of this ingestion that it
does from email and calendar and
contacts and all that.
But, it also can vectorize, turn it into
vector embeddings, and then allow you to
query it semantically with natural
language, not keywords, but ask smart
questions. In order to do that, G brain
requires an API to do those vector
embeddings.
It suggests using an Open AI API to do
that. That's what I use. And so, I have
an Open AI account specifically for
having access to this API on point in
order to do that. Again, you don't need
to understand any of these things.
You're like, "Oh man, this guy lost me.
I'm not technical. He's talking about
You don't need to understand any of
that." When you install G brain, it's
going to say, "Hey, get me a token.
Get me this API token." And I'll give
you step-by-step instructions to go sign
in to OpenAI, grab this token, and give
it to your
Hermes agent that's configuring your G
brain, and it'll put it in, and then
you'll get a tiny little bill from
OpenAI for API usage for doing this.
It's not a lot of money, even if like
mine's over 10,000 now of these contacts
and entities that are in there.
But, you're going to need this, and so
it's important to know that. Uh
you don't need this. This is my company,
uh Mind Studio Remy. I have it because I
have access to it, and why not? The
reason if you wanted to have it is it
gives you access to over 200 AI models
from all kinds of providers, and just
meters you for usage
uh uh of APIs, a bunch are more or less
expensive than these other models. Here,
it's mostly used for image and video
generation and doing deep research, and
then periodically, again, kind of
programmatically creating video. So,
it's great that being able to create
video clips and and and put them
together and apply
um um um you know, voiceover on them and
and captions and all of that. My Hermes
agent can do all of that automatically.
The reason it can do that without me
having a bunch of other accounts is I
just have one Mind Studio account that
gives me access to all these other
tools. Okay. Uh then uh there if you
want to communicate with your Hermes
agent beyond just in front of your
computer, you're going to need to
message it somehow. It supports WhatsApp
and all these other things. A popular
one is Telegram. I use that. Do I love
Telegram? No, I don't love Telegram. Uh
whatever, there it is,
uh Telegram. Uh do I um
Do I you know, uh do I have anything
else to to say about it? Guess not. Pick
your messenger of choice, configure it,
it's easy. We also use Slack. And so
this thing is connected to Slack. I just
logged it into Slack. And it's able to
read Slack. I don't go to Slack. I don't
have time to do it. And so my Hermes
agent watches all our Slack when there's
and summarizes everything for me. When
there's things to know, it it pings me
if they're important or I look at it
whenever I want. And then when I need to
respond, I go to Slack. But this thing
is doing all my Slack reading.
Otherwise, like that that used to take a
lot of time. There's no reason for me to
do that. Most things weren't for me.
Most things are not what I needed to
know at that time. They were just
interruptive. I don't get interrupted by
that anymore. Okay. Uh it's also
connected to I have two email accounts,
one at mindstudio.ai, one at goremy.ai.
This thing monitors both of my accounts,
reads all my emails. It triages them. It
pulls out all the things that are
relevant of new contacts I'm
communicating with, automatically adds
them to Gbrain, automatically goes and
enriches them, and understands what
they're all about, what they care about
now, who they're connected to.
You know, again, really tries to
understand who is this person and how
should we fit them into this graph of
people connected
and and doing that. Uh
Those of you that know me on LinkedIn
know that I'm a heavy user on LinkedIn.
I have lots of connections on LinkedIn.
LinkedIn does not have an API.
And and so you can't connect to LinkedIn
via API.
But these agents are able to do all
kinds of other things to connect to
LinkedIn. I redacted this thing here.
Actually, I didn't write this document.
I asked Watson to write all of these
documents. I didn't write any part of
any of these documents. Well, Watson
explained all the things that we've done
together. And and so
yeah, so it's all right. There's nothing
actually here that's like nefarious or
anything like that. But what I'm saying
is like there there's some things steps
that you need to take to configure your
browser here on your thing to be able to
connect to your LinkedIn and do that.
But, this thing is connected to
LinkedIn, can see all my stuff, and can
put people into G brain and all of that.
Uh same thing with Twitter, okay? Uh
we'll get into that some more in the
skills. Um
and then uh it does a lot of data
enrichment, right? And so, again,
there's a lot of public publicly
available data. Cool. We've got like all
this data publicly available or in my
email and things like that. Um and um uh
but, you really need to enrich all of
that. And so, there you need third-party
services in order to be able to do that.
First of all, your agent needs the
ability to search, as I mentioned uh I
mentioned. So, you need to configure a
search API. Uh one I used to use a lot
is is Brave. And there's many others. At
this moment, I'm running you.com. Uh
that's been great. And so, this Watson
uses it for all types of searches. And
that's constantly happening. Like, all
day long it's searching and doing stuff.
Okay. Another service that I subscribe
to is called PDL, uh People Data Labs.
You can just Google it, you'll find the
link. And it's uh it it's a database,
basically, uh that's a well
uh
uh cleaned and and well-formatted
database. And it's a paid service. But,
instead of going and looking for things
online, trying to put together pieces,
sometimes it's just easier to ask PDL to
get you all the data, and it gets you
all the data. And so, I have ex-
extremely uh uh detailed enrichment of
people. I understand all the things,
basically, about them. Another thing is
Now, I don't send out automatic emails
from this, uh
uh although you can. And but, I do have
an account on ZeroBounce uh bounce. And
this is very important that if you do
end up allowing your agent to send
emails to email accounts you don't know
that might be the wrong email and
they're going to bounce. It's really
important to first check that these
accounts are valid before sending a
message is otherwise you're going to
burn out your email account. You're
going to get flagged for spam and and
that's that. And so ZeroBounce is a
popular service that allows you to
basically make sure that the emails that
you're about to send to are valid
emails.
Uh here internally we use Fireflies and
so Fireflies follows me around to all
the meetings. Also Zoom is always doing
transcriptions. And so we have access to
all the things that I talk about, you
know, to all our various partners and
customers and etc. And all of that gets
ingested
um
into G Brain and and you know other uh
processes that are running that that
that need to take action, right? Uh also
obviously we're all running on on
Google. So this thing has access to
Gmail. Uh the way uh when it has an
output, when if it generates something
like for example, these documents that
it created, it puts it into a Google
Drive I created for it. And it's created
a folder on my Google Drive and said
that you know, whenever you have an
output, put it up there. And so it just
like writes things to Google Drive
instead of writing them just to locally
to the to the computer itself. Because
I've got a bunch other computers, I want
the ability to easily access them. And
so having a uh
uh a centralized bucket of any sort is
really valuable in running these things.
Uh also if you're running, you know,
multiple agents uh and they need to
share state in any way, you need some
centralized
um you know, data repository or state
repository in in in order to be able to
run these. Okay. Uh and then again, so
it creates Google Sheets and Docs and
can edit all of them. Like it can do all
the things I can do.
Uh another thing that's important here
is um
again, Watson runs on one machine here
in my in my office, but I have another
machine that's my primary machine. I
have a laptop that I use in other
places. And so, I need, for example, the
ability to get access to
um
this mission control. What is this? This
mission control is actually a a server
that was built by Watson. So, Watson
built a server
that runs on the Watson machine. And
that server creates this front end, this
interactive front end that I call
mission control,
that gives me access to all the
features, basically, of Watson. But the
problem is, how can I get to this thing
if it's here, you know, in my local area
network and I'm out on the internet
somewhere? Well, in order to be able to
do that, we need to to install a piece
of software. And kind of the most
popular one, whoops, is is called
Tailscale. Again, I'll give you links to
all of this stuff. It's free.
You go in and it creates, basically, a
tunnel between any machine, my laptop,
to Watson, this Mac mini I've got here
to Watson. And so, whenever I load up a
URL to a server that's running on
Watson, it can go through and and and I
can connect to that URL, even though
it's not on the public network. This is
basically on a private wide area
network, okay, that it's able to
connect. So, you you're going to need
this. Another thing, again, if you want
to remotely manage this thing, I'm
running a very popular thing here called
Parsec. Again, Parsec is an application
that's installed on both computers that
allows me to see the screen. This is
exactly what I see on my Watson screen
here. Now, we're seeing it here, and I
can interact with Watson using this
desktop mirroring. This is really
valuable to have. Also free. And so, um
that that's my stack here.
Um Obsidian, I've already shown you, is
important for G brain and also
visualizations of that. Uh and so it
creates all of these pages for each one
of these. Um
whenever things get in uh enriched, they
they get uh written here. And so G brain
manages the back end, Obsidian is the
front end. Obsidian's how Dimitri
navigates.
Um
uh there are a bunch of other things
that Mind Studio is used for here.
Again, you guys can have this document,
but this this isn't a sales pitch for
Mind Studio.
Uh
Zoom. So, we're on Zoom. Whenever a Zoom
is done,
uh it instantly gets ingested into uh
into Watson and gets processed and gets
enriched. And so it pulls out all of the
follow-ups. It can draft follow-up
emails. It extracts all the contacts,
all the action items, relationship
contacts. So, if you talk to me on Zoom,
you're going to be in my database. I'm
going to know a lot about you. And now
I'm going to be able to leverage our
relationship and be a good friend. My
goal is to help you be successful in in
in your endeavors and you can help me be
successful in mine. And this is really
valuable.
Uh also, I have a bunch of things that
are running
uh again, as these like cron jobs as
they're called, that are monitoring the
space that I'm in. My job is to run a
venture-backed company and I need to
understand what's happening in the world
of AI. That's impossible to do.
It's insane. And so I can't possibly do
it and so I don't do it. And so I've got
multiple processes that are running now.
We're going to run out of time here. Not
going to be able to get through
you know, all the stuff. Uh I'll do more
of these classes and again, I'll answer
you guys' questions here in a moment and
also in the school. But I wanted to dive
deeper into this. This is really
powerful. It's allowed me not to waste
my time trying to drink from a fire hose
in order to be able to understand the
important things that that are happening
here.
Um
And yeah, I'll kind of give you some
additional details here in how this like
pipeline works that ingests things and
and runs in it.
Um
I'm going to skip all of this here for
now, but again, you guys can get this
document. One final thing before I take
question, I'll run through this very
quickly.
Uh I assume a bunch of you have heard of
this term called skills.
So, agents
all agents have this ability to have
these things called skills. A skill is
simply a way for you to be able to more
precisely explain to an agent how to do
something, right? Think of it in that
way. Okay. And so, I've got a bunch of
skills that Watson and I have created
here. I enumerate all the skills here
for you. Again, you guys are going to
get this. You can look at them. So, I'm
going to quickly go through it. Uh
writing, I have a really awesome, finely
tuned now,
writing skill that allows Watson to
write all kinds of things for me from
long form to short form to post to all
kinds of things. It it never sort of
writes and posts,
right? Uh but it can it can propose
things to me.
And that helps me like it can watch the
world of AI and synthesize it and then
write something
clearly communicating to me what I
should have learned if I wasted all my
time watching it. And then I can choose
it. I can repost it. I can do whatever.
Okay. Uh there's another skill here
specifically for writing about Remy.
Again, that's my day job and and so,
knows all about Remy. It knows exactly
what kind of the narrative is and like
what not to do,
you know, blah blah blah. Uh
I am not sending out cold emails, but I
did implement a system that's able to do
that. Again, I'm experimenting with
these things.
Um
uh
I think it's really valuable to try
things. And the thing that I've been
doing is raising another round for Emmy.
And so I'm reaching out to investors.
I'm like, can I automate that? The
answer is hell yes. And and And if you
like turn this on, then you can go wild
with sales and all kinds of other
things. There's plenty of people online
that also point in this. I've
implemented my own. I've tested it. It
It's crazy powerful. Uh and this is a
skill that knows how to write cold
emails specifically to investors,
specifically about Rammy.
Very powerful.
Um there's all of this contact
enrichment, again, for the CRM.
Um
a skill that specifically talks about
how to fetch things from Zoom and Google
Calendar. And so that explains the to
the agent how to be efficient at pulling
all of these things and when to do it
and how to do that and all of that. Um
lots of monitoring, as I mentioned. And
so I'm watching the web, social media. I
realize things that are happening before
other people realize things are
happening because I'm not doing it. I've
got agents that are filtering the noise.
If you just look at like trending on
Twitter,
well, that's overall trending. That's
irrelevant. I want to know what's
trending with the people that are
important to me.
And I get to see what's trending with
them. I get to see what they're asking
for help with. And my system says, "Hey,
you can help this person." And I go and
I help them.
And they say, "Wow, thank you for
helping me." And that makes me feel good
and makes them feel good. And that
builds amazing relationships. Okay. It
does lots of things here specifically on
monitoring its own spend, as I
mentioned, right? So multiple skills for
spend
uh tracking. Um
and whatever, many other things. Okay,
so I'm going to stop here. Again, as I'm
experimenting with these formats and
trying to get all of you folks together,
there are lots and lots of things here.
I got through
60%, let's say. There's much more. I'll
make sure I'll do more of these and get
through. In the meantime, let me take
some questions here for 5 minutes. And
then again, as I promised you, if you
guys go to that school community and you
ask questions, go wild. I promise to
answer all questions. I know there's a
bunch of people pending. I need to
approve you. So, I will uh later. So,
don't don't be afraid again. If all of a
sudden I don't get your question here,
here's another link to that. You guys
can go there, sign up, completely free,
and and I'll answer your questions.
Okay. Uh Josh, do you want to throw some
questions?
>> Yeah, absolutely.
Uh great session, Dmitri. So, first
question is how does G brain manage
memory retrieval at scale? So, when the
memory gets bigger and bigger, what
impact does it have?
>> Um
it it's a geeky geeked-out thing that is
not going to relate to everybody here on
this, but it's well-documented. You You
can go and just do the research on that.
If not, again, ping me. I'll take you
offline there. It's It's It's a bit
geeky if we start talking about like
what things you need to make to to
change as you scale. If you're just an
individual, again, at this moment with
10,000 contacts that are extremely
well-researched, I haven't had to do
anything special for it, but you can
implement G brain at a company level,
which is really really interesting.
They're doing that at Y Combinator. And
so, there's some things you need to do
for that. If you get much larger data
sets that you're working with than I'm
working with, there are some things that
you can do. But again, let's take that
offline uh and and so, um keep keep
questions more general. Mhm.
>> [clears throat]
>> Yeah, sounds good. Um a lot of people
have been asking about the security and
how that compares with uh Open Claw.
So, I mean
>> Yeah, look, so really important to think
about that about security because like
what am I saying to you in download some
piece of software from the internet,
install it on your computer, give it
access to do all these things on your
computer, read all your emails, and use
your browser, whatever, connect it to
some model, and then say go. That seems
like
no uh no no no from any security
posture. Uh but look, I think uh it is a
trade-off at this moment, and most
people uh start by installing one of
these agents on a separate computer,
which mine is installed on a separate
computer, and giving it its own
credentials. Don't give it access to
your email. Create a separate email for
it. You can forward emails automatically
from your email to its email, and so it
can see your emails, and you can sort of
keep it at arm's length. I've done that
now for a few months many many times.
I've gotten really comfortable with
that. I understand where there are, you
know, potential vulnerabilities. Uh this
thing runs a daily security audit and
scan uh to make sure that all things are
are are buttoned up. So, I am not afraid
to have this thing have access to all of
my credentials. It does. The only thing
it doesn't have access to is like my
banking information. But other than
that, it has all my work access stuff,
and and it can do it. So, uh I guess my
advice is um
put it on a separate computer, uh play
around with it a bit till you feel
comfortable, and then again, just read
some things uh uh about it, and you'll
start to realize, I think, what I
realized, which is it's generally safe
enough now with Hermes
uh to log it [clears throat] in and and
let it use your credentials.
>> Great. And um some other questions
coming through is about Anthropic and
using uh
using the Anthropic Anthropic
subscription for your Hermes. Is that
still possible? People are mentioning
there's some pricing changes. that's
>> I'm using. The way that this works is um
so you need to install Claude code uh
from Anthropic. So this is again
piece of software. You can download it
for free. You need to have a pro
account. So you need to have at least a
$20 a month account in order to be able
to use that. Once you install Claude
code on your computer, then when you
install Hermes, Hermes will detect that
Claude code you you install Claude
Claude code, you log in and Hermes will
detect that you have Claude code
instance logged in
and will [clears throat] ask you if you
want it to basically just proxy itself
through that. And you say yes and you're
logged in to your subscription on um
Anthropic.
No no problems.
>> Wait, um one other question that I'm
seeing is um
are there use cases for using Hermes
across a team or like inside an
organization? Like all will you be able
to collaborate as a team with Hermes and
G brain?
>> Yeah, I mean that question's a bit I
think uh
there are many questions in that. So let
me answer a bunch of them. Uh one is you
can run
uh your team can each run each person
can run one or many instances of a
Hermes agent, right? And uh
and those agents can work individually
or they can collaborate. In order for
them to be able to collaborate, uh they
need to know about one another and
either expose ports using again these
things like Tailscale that I show you in
this document uh and also have some
central, you know, state management
thing like Google Drive or Dropbox or
you know, AWS uh you know, anything
that's got some kind of a
a place where it can read and write
things from so in order to be able to
maintain state and documents.
Um
uh and and yes, lots of people are doing
that now in organizations. Again, you
You just Google for it or on YouTube
you'll see people talking about that. Uh
also, with G Brains specifically that I
mentioned, I think there's an awesome
opportunity if you want to to to go and
do it and play around with it for uh
setting up a company-wide G Brain
where you set up a Hermes agent, you set
up a company-wide G Brain, uh and it
allows different you uh users in your
company, different people, to be able in
a sense to log into that system and be
able to use all of that. And so, they
get G Brain, but there's also the
company G Brain. And so, you're like
capturing from all these other Hermes
agents, from all these other people, all
of this knowledge. And it all goes into
a central repository, everything gets
graphed centrally, and you get the
company version of this thing that I've
been raving about. Um uh Gary's talked
about this a bunch on various podcasts.
I haven't implemented it here yet. Just
have been busy, you know, with all the
other stuff. But But uh
I think it makes a lot of sense, and I
think if you want to do it like that, I
think that's worth doing.
>> Great. Yeah, I think those were the main
big questions. Um there's a lot of
smaller questions that I think people
can ask uh through that school
community. So, we'll make sure to share
the recording and all the links that
you've shown today uh to everyone here
after this session.
>> Yeah, and like one final thing as as we
leave here, thanks folks for hanging out
here. And And again, listening to
>> [laughter]
>> to me ramble at you. Hopefully it was a
little entertaining, and maybe you got
some good things out of it. Uh if to
leave you with I again my summarize it
as like um
it's important, I think. I highly
recommend uh put
putting some time into this, learning
about these personal agents,
setting them up, learning how to
interact with them, geeking out on some
of these things on configuration,
starting to think about what would it
mean if I understood my entire you know
friend and business network in in such
ways and like the kinds of things I can
do all of the opportunities for
automation and and
don't sit this out. This is not a fact.
The self-driving computers maybe we
should call them instead of personal
agents are here. Jensen Huang is right.
This is the new computer
and those of us that know how to do this
better than others.
We'll be we'll have an extreme
advantage.
Yeah, if you're still doing things
manually.
You can't possibly compete with somebody
who set up
one or many [clears throat] agents and
has this kind of things. All right guys,
thanks so much. Good to see you.
Go to this community again. I'll answer
all your questions and
and
yeah, looking forward to to connecting
with all you guys. We're not connected
on LinkedIn. Please find me and connect
and great to talk to you. Take care.
>> Thank you all. Bye.